

+27679722872

eddychetz@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/eddwin-cheteni-profile

www.eddiecheteni.netlify.app



AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner with 4 years of Data Science teaching experience and 8 years of high school mathematics teaching. Seeks to improve data-driven decision-making for Belgium Campus and beyond through the collection of data based on measurable goals or KPIs, analyzing patterns and facts from these insights, and utilizing them to develop strategies and processes that benefit the education and other business entities in a variety of ways.



EXPERIENCE

Jun 2018- date Senior Data Science Lecturer - Belgium Campus ITversity NPC1 (South Africa)

- Excellent in lecturing Data Science Modules: Calculus, Statistics, Research Methods, Machine Learning, and Linear Programming in a Hybrid setup environment,
- Supervising undergraduate students in Research and, marking and moderation,
- Assistance in Curriculum and Syllabus Development,
- Take part in bridging program teaching to first year students +and winter school program to matric students,
- Marking, Setting, and Moderation of Students' assessments (Assignments, Tests, and Examinations).
- Offering Extra Classes to Students for exam preparations.

May 2016-Mar 2018 Mathematics teacher - Chaplin High School (ZW)

- Teaching ordinary level and advanced level Mathematics,
- Taking part in curriculum development workshops,
- Raised pass rate by 20% in 2016,
- Marking, Setting, and Schemes of Work preparation,
- Participating in sporting activities (soccer and darts),

Jan 2011-Mar 2016 Mathematics and Computer Applications teacher - Tongogara High School (ZW)

- Promote excellent teaching and learning of Mathematics and Computers,
- Responsible for the drawing up of syllabuses/schemes of work,
- Participate in vacation mathematics teaching programs,
- Achieved 100% Advanced level pass rate in 2016.
- Coach the soccer team to the National level.



SOFT SKILLS

- Problem-solving
- Storytelling
- Interpersonal Skills
- Critical Thinking

******Expect

*****Advanced

*****Advanced



TECHNICAL SKILLS

Machine Learning Algorithms (Classification, Clustering, and Regression)

R Programming, Python, SPSS, Minitab, C, & Excel, SQL, VBA

Machine Learning IDEs (RStudio, JupyterLab, IBM Watson Studio)

Machine Learning Libraries (Keras, TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn),

Data Wrangling (Libs: Numpy, scipy, pandas), Web Scrapping (rvest,)

• Data Visualization tools: Python and R Libraries (matplotlib, seaborn, ggplot), IBM-Cognos, PowerBI, and Tableau.

Cloud Computing platforms (Azure, IBM Cloud, AWS)

Collaboration platforms (Github, RPubs)

E-Learning Platforms (Teams, Zoom, Slack, FlipGrid)

*****Advanced

****Advanced

Expect

*****Advanced

**** Advanced

**** Advanced

*****Advanced

**** Advanced

**** Advanced



EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATION

Jan 2022-Dec 2024 Masters of Science in Financial Engineering

WorldQuant University - Online

Aug 2013-Dec 2015 Masters of Science in Operations Research and Statistics

National University of Science & Technology - ZW

Aug 2006-Nov 2010 Bachelor of Science (Hons) in Mathematics *Midlands State University-ZW*



CERTIFICATION

Date	Institution/organization	Certificate/Course/Training
2021	AWS	AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (Validation No: P6P78LVLGMBQQFCX)
2021	IBM	IBM Data Analyst Professional Certificate
	IBM	Python Data Science Professional Certificate
	IBM	IBM Data Science Professional Certificate
	IBM	<u>Data Analysis and Visualization Fundamentals Professional Certificate</u>
2021	Harvardx	Data Science Professional Certificate
2020	IBM	Data Science Foundations Professional Certificate



RESEARCH INTERESTS

 Artificial Intelligence, Financial Time Series, Geo-Spatial Analysis, Network Analytics, Text Analysis for Business Analytics, Machine Learning Applications, and Credit Risk Modeling.



REFERENCES

Lettitia Van Der Belgium Campus ITversity NPC 1

Merwe HR Manager vandermerwe.l@belgiumcampus.ac.za

• Stanley Chinkono Chaplin High School, +263 77 534 1185 info@chaplinhighschool.com

Morale Ngwabi

Tongogara High School, +263 77 566 3971

Head of Department (Maths)